<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>migration | </title>
    <link>https://fullertonrico.github.io/tags/migration/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://fullertonrico.github.io/tags/migration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>migration</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://fullertonrico.github.io/media/icon_hu31a02fe58960b2182481055d1a955312_128444_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>migration</title>
      <link>https://fullertonrico.github.io/tags/migration/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grieving in the “Golden Cage”: How Unauthorized Immigrants Mourn from Afar</title>
      <link>https://fullertonrico.github.io/research/grieving-in-the-golden-cage-how-unauthorized-immigrants-mourn-from-afar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fullertonrico.github.io/research/grieving-in-the-golden-cage-how-unauthorized-immigrants-mourn-from-afar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the past four decades, the United States has created a population of long-term unauthorized immigrants. As this population ages, issues of death and dying are increasingly salient. Though we know much about how families maintain close bonds despite geographic distance, death and dying remain undertheorized in transnational family scholarship. Yet the death of a family member can significantly impact family structure and functions. Based on ethnographic and interview data collected from 2017–2023 with unauthorized Mexican immigrants and their families, this study examines how unauthorized immigrants anticipate and mourn the death of family members in their community of origin and how their undocumented status creates challenges for themselves and their families after a transnational death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that the specter of transnational death shapes the emotional wellbeing of older unauthorized immigrants years before they experience it. Undocumented status creates and compounds transnational grief, leading to additional challenges. Individuals use a variety of strategies to grieve, including mourning by proxy, paying for funeral expenses, and participating virtually. This research advances immigration scholarship by uncovering underappreciated social and emotional penalties imposed by current immigration laws and highlighting the value of mourning as a collective ritual –– the absence of which has lasting costs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aging without a Safety Net: Challenges Faced by Unauthorized Immigrants at the End of Their Working Years</title>
      <link>https://fullertonrico.github.io/research/aging-without-a-safety-net-challenges-faced-by-unauthorized-immigrants-at-the-end-of-their-working-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fullertonrico.github.io/research/aging-without-a-safety-net-challenges-faced-by-unauthorized-immigrants-at-the-end-of-their-working-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Labor laws relegate unauthorized immigrants to low-paying jobs during their working years, while other laws exclude unauthorized immigrants from accessing safety-net institutions designed to support older people, such as Social Security or Medicare (Ayón et al. 2020; Flores Morales 2021; Stanley et al. 2020; Torres et al. 2016). This makes the transition out of work carry particular challenges not borne by other populations. At the same time, immigrants in this position describe economic struggles because they can no longer work due to bodily limitations and/or age discrimination, which complicates staying in the United States even if they would prefer to do so. How do older unauthorized immigrants navigate these pressures and uncertainties as their working years come to an end? How does ceasing to work challenge the identities of people defined and valued primarily as laborers in U.S. society –– and how are these challenges gendered? How do unauthorized immigrants plan for their futures and deal with uncertainty at this stage of life? What sources of formal and informal support are they able to access?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unos Allá, Otros Aquí: Transnational Parenting and Digital Communication across the Mexico-U.S. Border</title>
      <link>https://fullertonrico.github.io/research/unos-alla-otros-aqui-transnational-parenting-and-digital-communication-across-the-mexico-u.s.-border/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fullertonrico.github.io/research/unos-alla-otros-aqui-transnational-parenting-and-digital-communication-across-the-mexico-u.s.-border/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As border walls grow, security tightens, and arrests climb for undocumented migrants crossing the Mexico-U.S. border, physical visits have become increasingly difficult for families living on both sides. At the same time, communication technologies have improved and cheapened, so families are physically divided but digitally close. This paper examines how parents and children at younger and older ages navigate the juxtaposition of decades-long physical absence and near-daily communication as they work to maintain the bonds of family across the border. What is it like to migrate during a time marked by increasingly closed borders and increasingly open communication? More specifically, how do families separated by a border they cannot cross use technology to maintain relationships? Drawing on binational fieldwork with families straddling the Mexico-U.S. border, I find that immigrant parents often have children in both countries. As parents use technology to forge bonds of “digital siblinghood” between children who have never physically met and face the prospect of leaving behind some children to reunite with others, they fear that unifying their families may be impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Because There Was No Line: How Return Migration in Later Life Impacts Unauthorized Immigrants and Separates their Families</title>
      <link>https://fullertonrico.github.io/research/because-there-was-no-line-how-return-migration-in-later-life-impacts-unauthorized-immigrants-and-separates-their-families/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fullertonrico.github.io/research/because-there-was-no-line-how-return-migration-in-later-life-impacts-unauthorized-immigrants-and-separates-their-families/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Immigrant integration is intuitively understood as a function of time: the longer someone is in the U.S., the more “American” they feel and the more they participate in civic life. However, undocumented immigrants in today’s era of restricted immigration find diminishing opportunities for integration. Regardless of how long they have spent in the United States, they increasingly find that the roots they put down are at risk of being dug up and discarded by the deportation regime, or that it is difficult to put down roots at all because their rights are so curtailed (Bean, Brown, and Bachmeier 2015, Leyro 2018). These hardships do not only impact unauthorized immigrants themselves but extend to their families (see, e.g., Dreby 2015).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because immigration reform with a path to legalization has failed to pass for nearly four decades, a significant share of the unauthorized population is experiencing a demographic transition: people who migrated after the Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986 are aging out of work without a path to citizenship. More than a quarter of unauthorized immigrants are estimated to be 45 years or older (Ro, Van Hook, Walsemann 2022, López et al. 2021, Migration Policy Institute 2019). This is especially the case for unauthorized immigrants from Mexico. Among Mexican immigrants without authorization –– who make up about half of the undocumented population –– nearly 85 percent have been living in the U.S. for over a decade (López et al. 2021). They are also overrepresented in the “Entry Without Inspection” category, which has been more penalized and prevented from adjusting legal status (López 2021).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unable to adjust their immigration status, unauthorized immigrants may choose –– or be forced –– to return to their communities of origin. In this paper, I draw on fieldwork and in-depth interviews with older return migrants in Puebla and Tlaxcala, Mexico as well as with their family members who remain in New York City in order to understand how return migration in later life impacts older immigrants and their families. I find that return migration in later life due to undocumented status happens in a variety of ways, ranging from hasty, unplanned returns due to deportation to well-resourced, planned returns as a retirement strategy. Regardless of the reason for their return, the departure of older migrants disrupts their lives as well as the lives of their families, reducing their ability to give and receive care. Return migration also transforms familial roles, especially for U.S. citizen grandchildren who often begin to travel alone to visit their grandparents because they are the only members of their families who can cross the U.S.–Mexico border legally. Taken together, this research illustrates the power that U.S. immigration policies exert over family formation –– fundamentally restructuring families that would otherwise live together and provide valuable support to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
