<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://fullertonrico.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://fullertonrico.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description></description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://fullertonrico.github.io/media/icon_hu31a02fe58960b2182481055d1a955312_128444_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://fullertonrico.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feminist Interview Methods and Research Ethics</title>
      <link>https://fullertonrico.github.io/research/feminist-interview-methods-and-research-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fullertonrico.github.io/research/feminist-interview-methods-and-research-ethics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scholars have critiqued feminist ethnographic research methods because of their potential to create a false sense of friendship and intimacy or to downplay power differences, rather than acknowledging that unequal power dynamics cannot be completely eliminated (see, e.g., Kirsch 2005). Drawing on interviews and fieldwork conducted in the United States and Mexico between 2017–2020 on the subjects of transnational relationships and migration, this paper examines how to use interview methods to address unequal power dynamics and increase transparency. In doing research that uses participant-observation and semi-structured interviews, I find that interviews can be a powerful tool for ensuring participants understand what I am studying, setting clearer boundaries, and creating space for participants to shape our research agendas. Sharing my own experiences as an immigrant who maintains close transnational relationships also allows me to increase transparency about my social location and the ways it might limit my perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grieving in the “Golden Cage”: How Unauthorized Immigrants Mourn from Afar</title>
      <link>https://fullertonrico.github.io/research/grieving-in-the-golden-cage-how-unauthorized-immigrants-mourn-from-afar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fullertonrico.github.io/research/grieving-in-the-golden-cage-how-unauthorized-immigrants-mourn-from-afar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the past four decades, the United States has created a population of long-term unauthorized immigrants. As this population ages, issues of death and dying are increasingly salient. Though we know much about how families maintain close bonds despite geographic distance, death and dying remain undertheorized in transnational family scholarship. Yet the death of a family member can significantly impact family structure and functions. Based on ethnographic and interview data collected from 2017–2023 with unauthorized Mexican immigrants and their families, this study examines how unauthorized immigrants anticipate and mourn the death of family members in their community of origin and how their undocumented status creates challenges for themselves and their families after a transnational death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that the specter of transnational death shapes the emotional wellbeing of older unauthorized immigrants years before they experience it. Undocumented status creates and compounds transnational grief, leading to additional challenges. Individuals use a variety of strategies to grieve, including mourning by proxy, paying for funeral expenses, and participating virtually. This research advances immigration scholarship by uncovering underappreciated social and emotional penalties imposed by current immigration laws and highlighting the value of mourning as a collective ritual –– the absence of which has lasting costs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unos Allá, Otros Aquí: Transnational Parenting and Digital Communication across the Mexico-U.S. Border</title>
      <link>https://fullertonrico.github.io/research/unos-alla-otros-aqui-transnational-parenting-and-digital-communication-across-the-mexico-u.s.-border/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fullertonrico.github.io/research/unos-alla-otros-aqui-transnational-parenting-and-digital-communication-across-the-mexico-u.s.-border/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As border walls grow, security tightens, and arrests climb for undocumented migrants crossing the Mexico-U.S. border, physical visits have become increasingly difficult for families living on both sides. At the same time, communication technologies have improved and cheapened, so families are physically divided but digitally close. This paper examines how parents and children at younger and older ages navigate the juxtaposition of decades-long physical absence and near-daily communication as they work to maintain the bonds of family across the border. What is it like to migrate during a time marked by increasingly closed borders and increasingly open communication? More specifically, how do families separated by a border they cannot cross use technology to maintain relationships? Drawing on binational fieldwork with families straddling the Mexico-U.S. border, I find that immigrant parents often have children in both countries. As parents use technology to forge bonds of “digital siblinghood” between children who have never physically met and face the prospect of leaving behind some children to reunite with others, they fear that unifying their families may be impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://fullertonrico.github.io/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fullertonrico.github.io/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aging without a Safety Net: Challenges Faced by Unauthorized Immigrants at the End of Their Working Years</title>
      <link>https://fullertonrico.github.io/research/aging-without-a-safety-net-challenges-faced-by-unauthorized-immigrants-at-the-end-of-their-working-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fullertonrico.github.io/research/aging-without-a-safety-net-challenges-faced-by-unauthorized-immigrants-at-the-end-of-their-working-years/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Returned to Mexico: Older Return Migration and Immigrant Exclusion</title>
      <link>https://fullertonrico.github.io/research/returned-to-mexico-older-return-migration-and-immigrant-exclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fullertonrico.github.io/research/returned-to-mexico-older-return-migration-and-immigrant-exclusion/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
